<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: travel | TimBerglund.com]]></title>
  <link href="http://tlberglund.github.com/blog/categories/travel/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://tlberglund.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-12-14T07:46:26-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://tlberglund.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Tim Berglund]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[tlberglund@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journey Zone 2015: PolarZone]]></title>
    <link href="http://tlberglund.github.com/blog/2015/12/14/journey-zone-2015-polarzone/"/>
    <updated>2015-12-14T07:25:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://tlberglund.github.com/blog/2015/12/14/journey-zone-2015-polarzone</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The <a href="http://2015.javazone.no/">2015 JavaZone</a> was the same amazing event it always is: world-class speakers, JavaZone's ground-breaking <em>continuous food</em> concept, and an expo floor that's actually fun to walk around. Like any great conference, it's a place to learn and reconnect with friends—some whom I only get to see once a year.</p>

<p><a href="http://2015.javazone.no/journeyzone.html">JourneyZone</a>—the long weekend away someplace in Norway that JavaZone provides for its speakers after the conference—is always memorable, but this year was truly a once-in-a-lifetime experience. In commemoration, I present to you <em>Polar Zone 2015</em>:</p>

<p><iframe src="http://player.vimeo.com/video/148731531" width="600" height="338" class="center" frameborder="0" webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen></iframe></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[SurvivorZone Documentary]]></title>
    <link href="http://tlberglund.github.com/blog/2012/09/30/survivorzone-documentary/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-30T20:33:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://tlberglund.github.com/blog/2012/09/30/survivorzone-documentary</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I mentioned in my <a href="http://timberglund.com/blog/2012/09/17/javazone-2012/">last post</a> that JourneyZone had a few surprises this year—which surprises should perhaps not be all that surprising, given that we were riding mountain bikes in the same part of Norway that served as the <a href="http://images.wikia.com/starwars/images/c/cd/0_gps2.jpg">location for the Hoth scenes</a> in <em>The Empire Strikes Back</em>. (Thanks to <a href="http://blog.evilmonkeylabs.com/">Brendan McAdams</a> for that link.)</p>

<p>Whether we should have seen it coming or not, we had a great time. In fact, JourneyZone wasn't merely JourneyZone. Witness <em>SurvivorZone 2012</em>:</p>

<p><iframe src="http://player.vimeo.com/video/50468163" width="600" height="338" class="center" frameborder="0" webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen></iframe></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[JavaZone 2012]]></title>
    <link href="http://tlberglund.github.com/blog/2012/09/17/javazone-2012/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-17T11:59:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://tlberglund.github.com/blog/2012/09/17/javazone-2012</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>JavaZone 2012 is in the books now. I don't mind saying I <em>love</em> that show and the city it's in. Oslo might be an expensive place to visit, but it makes up for it by being beautiful and generally easy to get around.</p>

<p>This was my third <a href="http://jz12.java.no">JavaZone</a>, but my first as a GitHubber. I actually submitted my proposals to the show before even beginning to consider going to work for GitHub, so there was no Git to be found in my talks as originally planned. Happily, the schedule had some holes open up at the last minute, so I was able to give three talks: a brand new lightning talk on Git internals, my talk on software architecture and form entitled <em><a href="https://vimeo.com/album/2079027/video/49367407">Then Our Buildings Shape Us</a></em>, and an improvised <a href="https://vimeo.com/album/2079027/video/49444883">Advanced Git</a> talk containing some new material I have recently been testing out. The response to the latter on Twitter was especially enthusiastic, with more than a few people saying it was their favorite talk of the show. Thank you, Norway! Honestly, I love you too.</p>

<p><a href="http://s3.amazonaws.com/timberglund.com/photos/2012/09/agir-beer.jpg" class="fancybox left" title="This beer was actually in Flåm, not Myrdal "><img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/timberglund.com/photos/2012/09/agir-beer_m.jpg" width="300" height="200" alt="This beer was actually in Flåm, not Myrdal " /></a></p>

<p>Next was JourneyZone, rechristened "SurvivorZone" for its 2012 instance. JourneyZone is a three-day weekend trip to some exotic destination in Norway that the conference offers to its speakers. This year, JourneyZone started with a 22-mile mountain bike ride across the mountains of western Norway. This is typical summer fare for active Norwegians (and does not seem at all odd to this active Coloradan), but we just happened to get caught in a nasty bit of weather on Friday afternoon. Five hours of cycling through 35-mph winds and freezing rain will <em>take the fight out of you</em>. Let's just say I have never tasted beer as good as the beer I had in Myrdal that night, and leave it at that.</p>

<p><a href="http://s3.amazonaws.com/timberglund.com/photos/2012/09/flam.jpg" class="fancybox right" title="Outside our hotel in Aurland "><img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/timberglund.com/photos/2012/09/flam_m.jpg" width="300" height="200" alt="Outside our hotel in Aurland " /></a></p>

<p>After thawing out and resting up, we took a train to Flåm to rest for the day and tour one of Norway's largest microbreweries. If Flåm were trying not to be beautiful, it would count as the most spectacular failure known to the sons of men.</p>

<p>When we returned home on Sunday night, I hosted the second annual GitHub Oslo Drinkup.  Oslo developers came to talk about what they were doing with Git and with technology in general, joined by not a few JavaZone speakers and staff—Git fans all.</p>

<p><a href="http://s3.amazonaws.com/timberglund.com/photos/2012/09/oslo-drinkup.jpg" class="fancybox left" title="2012 The Octocat makes its appearance in Oslo "><img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/timberglund.com/photos/2012/09/oslo-drinkup.jpg" width="300" height="200" alt="2012 The Octocat makes its appearance in Oslo " /></a></p>

<p>Thanks to GitHub for the opportunity to evangelize our technology in places like this, to <a href="http://java.no">javaBin</a> and the JavaZone organizers for putting on such a great show. God willing, I will see you next September.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
